theparisreview.org 2019-12-10

# Paris Review - Writers, Quotes, Biography, Interviews, Artists

**1\. Overview**

This Privacy Policy is part of the Terms and Conditions of the Website (as defined in the [Terms and Conditions](https://www.theparisreview.org/terms-and-conditions)) and applies to all visitors to the Website, including persons who purchase products through the Website. This Privacy Policy describes what information we at The Paris Review Foundation, Inc. (the “Foundation”, “we”, “our” or “us”) collect from you and how we use that information. This Privacy Policy applies to any information collected by our Website, including your Personally Identifiable Information (as defined below). 

We may amend this Privacy Policy from time to time. We may notify you of any changes to this Privacy Policy by posting a notice on the Website or by contacting you through e-mail or other means so that you will always know what information we gather, how we might use that information, and when we will disclose that information. By using our Website, or any of the products or resources that we provide on our Website, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy. Your continued use of our Website following the posting of changes to this Privacy Policy will mean that you accept those changes.

If you access the Website from outside the United States, please be sure to review the sections of this Privacy Policy that are applicable to you.  For purposes of the European Union General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), the Foundation is the data controller. ** **

**2\. Collection and Use of Information**

**WHAT INFORMATION ABOUT YOU IS COLLECTED ON OUR WEBSITE?**

We collect information when you provide it to us that identifies you or can be used to identify or contact you, including your name, street address (for billing or shipping), email address, telephone number and billing and credit card information (“Personally Identifiable Information”).  We may collect Personally Identifiable Information from you in different manners and at different places on our Website, such as when you subscribe to the _Paris Review_ Newsletter, purchase a subscription to _The Paris Review_ , purchase any product from our online [**store**](https://www.theparisreview.org/store.php) (“Store”), or make a donation on the Website, Personally Identifiable Information is collected by us and by our third-party e-commerce partners Shopify.com and Strategic Fulfillment Services inc.. We collect Personally Identifiable Information from you when you voluntarily submit such information to us or when you use the Website.

In addition, we may automatically collect your IP address when you use the Website and we may use web beacons, web bugs, clear gifs, cookies and similar technologies (collectively, “Automatically Collected Data”) that automatically collect information from you as you use the Website.  This Automatically Collected Data also allows us to recognize you when you access the Website using different web browsers or devices.

**USE OF INFORMATION THAT WE COLLECT.**

In general, Personally Identifiable Information and other information collected on our Website to collect payments you made in our **[Store](https://www.theparisreview.org/store.php)** and to correspond with you, to process a donation or otherwise to follow up on any such transactions.  On occasion, we may use your Personally Identifiable Information to send you information on new products or upcoming events. However, if you do not wish to receive E-mailed marketing messages from us, please let us know by sending an E-mail to webmaster [at] theparisreview.org or writing us using the contact information on our **[Contact Page](https://www.theparisreview.org/contact)**.

We use Automatically Collected Data to improve our Website and for any other lawful business purpose, including without limitation, to determine which of our messages have been opened by recipients, so we can gauge the effectiveness of marketing campaigns, to control the display of ads, to track usage patterns, the movements of individual users, and your geographic location, to help diagnose problems with our servers, to gather broad demographic information, to analyze trends, to conduct research, to deliver editorial content, or to record registration and personalization information.

**WHEN WE DISCLOSE INFORMATION TO THIRD PARTIES.**

Except as set forth in this Privacy Policy, we will not disclose any information we gather from you on our Website.

We may employ independent contractors, vendors (such as our e-commerce partners) or suppliers (collectively, “Outside Contractors”) to provide specific services and products related to our Website or products, including but not limited to providing credit card processing and fraud screening, and fulfilling purchase orders.  Access to your Personally Identifiable Information by these Outside Contractors is limited to the information reasonably necessary in order for the Outside Contractors to perform their limited functions for us. We also require that these contractors (i) protect the privacy of your Personally Identifiable Information in a manner consistent with this Privacy Policy [and applicable law], and (ii) not use or disclose your Personally Identifiable Information for any purpose other than providing us with products or services for which we contracted.

In addition, through our Website, you may be given the opportunity to purchase (or obtain more information regarding) certain content, products, or services which are sold through a person or company other than us (collectively, “Third-Party Sellers”). Third-Party Sellers may request that you submit certain information to them in order to purchase their products or services or to obtain additional information from them.  By submitting the requested information, you affirmatively consent to have that information shared with the Third-Party Seller.  This information is used by the Third-Party Seller and may be subject to its privacy policy, which may be different from our Privacy Policy.  We do not otherwise share or disclose your Personally Identifiable Information with or to Third-Party Sellers.

We reserve the right to transfer information to a third party in the event of a sale, merger or other transfer of all or substantially all of the assets of the Foundation provided that the third party agrees to adhere to the terms of this Privacy Policy. We will notify users of any such transfer through notice on our Website and to the extent possible, through E-mail.

We may disclose your Personally Identifiable Information if we believe in good faith that we are required by law to do so, including in response to lawful requests from public and government authorities, which may include authorities outside your country of residence. We may disclose Personally Identifiable Information in special circumstances when we have reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to protect the safety and/or security of our users, our Website, or the general public.

**DOES THIS PRIVACY POLICY APPLY WHEN I LINK TO OTHER WEBSITES?**

Our Website contains links to third-party websites not owned or operated by the Foundation.  This Privacy Policy does not apply to the collection and use of any information gathered by or through any third-party websites, including any sites to which the Website links.  We are not responsible for the content, accuracy, privacy practices and performance of those websites.  We encourage you to be aware when our Website links to third-party websites and read the privacy policies or statements of each and every such website to understand what policies apply to their own collection and use of information.

**IS THE INFORMATION WE COLLECT SECURE?**

We strive to secure transmission of your Personally Identifiable Information from your computer to our servers through commercially reasonable administrative, technical, personnel and physical measures.  To help ensure the integrity and privacy of the Personally Identifiable Information you provide via the Internet at the time you purchase any product or donate online, the above mentioned third party e-commerce partners, Shopify.com and Strategic Fulfillment Services inc, provide Transport Layer Security (“TLS”) digital security.  Only employees who need access to your Personally Identifiable Information to perform a specific task or function are granted access to such Personally Identifiable Information.  Notwithstanding the foregoing, no employee of the Foundation will have access to your credit card information provided through this Website.

Notwithstanding the foregoing, you should be aware that there is always some risk involved in transmitting information over the Internet.  There is also some risk that others could find a way to thwart or bypass our security systems.  As a result, although we strive to protect your information, we cannot ensure or warrant the security and privacy of any information you transmit to us, and you do so at your own risk.  If you correspond with us by e-mail or a “Contact Us” feature on the Website, a third party could view the information you send in transit by such means.  We will have no liability for disclosure of your information due to errors or unauthorized acts of third parties during or after transmission.

**CHOICES THAT I HAVE REGARDING THE COLLECTION, DISCLOSURE, AND DISTRIBUTION OF PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION.**

Except as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy, we will only use Personally Identifiable Information for the purposes described above or as otherwise disclosed at the time we request such information from you.  You may “opt-out” of receiving our e-mail distribution by clicking the unsubscribe link within the e-mail you receive or by contacting our Postmaster at the address set out below.  Please understand that it may take us a few days to process any unsubscribe request.

**TRANSFERS OUTSIDE THE EEA.** **  
**

The information in this section is directed to those users located in the European Economic Area (“EEA”).

To process information of individuals for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy, we store and process all personal data in the United States and we provide such data to Outside Contractors that are located outside the EEA.  We may do so for the operation of the Website, to provide you with our products or services, for purposes of data analysis or where necessary for exercising, establishing or defending legal rights of the Foundation.

Non-EEA countries might not have the same legal framework for data protection as the EEA countries.  In particular, the United States may not provide a level of protection for personal data, or Personally Identifying Information, equivalent to that of the EEA.

**DO NOT TRACK DISCLOSURES.**

Some web browsers may transmit “do-not-track” (“DNT”) signals to mobile applications with which the user communicates.  We currently do not change our tracking practices in response to DNT settings in your web browser.  We may have our third-party partners, including web analytics companies, collect information about your online activities over time and across the Website.  These third parties may not change their tracking practices in response to DNT settings in your web browser.

**3\. General Information**

**ACCESSING, UPDATING AND CORRECTING YOUR PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION.**

You can always contact us in order to (1) access, update or correct your Personally Identifiable Information, (2) change your preferences with respect to communications and other information you may receive from us, or (3) delete the Personally Identifiable Information maintained about you on our systems, by contacting our Postmaster at the address set out below; however, some residual information may remain on back-up media and records of deletions. Such updates, corrections, changes and deletions will not have an effect on other information that we maintain, or information that we have provided to third parties in accordance with this Privacy Policy prior to such update, correction, change or deletion. We are unable to delete information from third-party databases.

In some jurisdictions, including in the countries of the EEA, you have the right, in certain circumstances, to (1) require us to delete your Personally Identifiable Information, (2) require us to restrict processing of your Personally Identifiable Information, (3) receive a copy of the Personally Identifiable Information you provided to us in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and/or instruct us to transmit that data to a third party; and (4) object to our continued processing of your Personally Identifiable Information for direct marketing or other purposes.  If you are resident in the EEA, you can exercise these rights free of charge by contacting our Postmaster at the address set out below.

**CHANGES TO THE PRIVACY POLICY.**

If, at any point, we decide to use Personally Identifiable Information in a manner we deem significantly different from that stated in this Privacy Policy, or that we otherwise disclosed to you, at the time it was collected, we will notify you by posting changes on our Website in this Privacy Policy, or by email or otherwise, and you will have a choice as to whether or not we use your Personally Identifiable Information in the new manner.  We may also make non-significant changes to our Privacy Policy that generally will not affect our use of your Personally Identifiable Information.

**CONTACT REGARDING PRIVACY QUESTIONS.**

If you have any questions about our Privacy Policy or believe that we are not abiding by its terms, please contact our Postmaster in either of the following ways:

E-mail our Postmaster   
webmaster [at] theparisreview.org

Or, write to our Postmaster at:  
The Paris Review Foundation, Inc.  
544 West 27th Street  
New York, NY 10001  
Attn: Postmaster

If you are located in the EEA and if you believe that we are not abiding by our Privacy Policy, you have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority of the EEA state where you work or live or where any alleged infringement of data protection laws occurred.

_Last updated: December 10, 2018_
